KONRAD KARANOWSKI

Machine Learning Researcher and Engineer

CONTACT

+48796062833

konrad.karanowski@gmail.com

Q Wroclaw, Poland

https://github.com/konrad-karanowski

https://konrad-karanowski.github.io

https://scholar.google.com/citations? user=_Cn3jmsAAAAJ&hl=pl

PROFILE

I am a machine learning researcher based in Wroclaw, Poland. I have over three years of experience in the field, both commercially and in academia. Along this journey, I've coauthored 12 scientific publications. My main interests include generative AI, probabilistic machine learning, AI in medicine and AI in biochemistry. I am currently collaborating with researchers from the Federal Institute of Technology Zurich (ETHZ) on the applications of artificial intelligence in electron cryomicroscopy (CryoEM).

SKILLS

• Used Technologies Python, Pandas, SQL, Matplotlib, Plotly, Jupyter Notebook, PyTorch, PyTorch

Lightning, Scikit-Learn, Numpy, OpenCV, Transformers, Diffusers, Git, DVC, Hydra,

Wandb, Linux

Known concepts
Neural Networks, Computer Vision, Natural Language Processing, Generative AI,

Probabilistic Machine Learning

Other skills Teamwork, Self-organisation, Scientific methodology

WORK EXPERIENCE

Machine Learning Researcher

TOOPLOOX

I am responsible on conducting research on Diffusion Models in order to improve their performance in the client's use-case scenarios.

Machine Learning Specialist

BIOCAN

I was responsible for applying generative models to capsule endoscopy images and developing new methods of data augmentation. I had the opportunity to work with models such as Denoising Diffusion Probabilistic Models or Latent Diffusion Models. My work resulted in a pipeline that improves the performance of classifiers for rare pathologies.

NLP Engineer / Researcher

August 2021 - February 2023

January 2023 - August 2024

August 2024 - present

CLARIN-PL

I was responsible for doing research on natural language processing in subjective tasks, taking into account the context of the user. I also worked on the development of an automatic speech recognition system for the Polish language. I had the opportunity to work with models such as Transformers, Whisper or Normalizing Flows. My work resulted in 5 scientific papers.

Junior Data Scientist (Intern)

September 2020 - January 2021

ESPORTSLABGG

I was working on image classification and object detection using neural networks. I have worked with models such as FasterRCNN or YOLO.

EDUCATION

Master's Degree in Artificial Intelligence

2023-2024 Final grade: A

WROCLAW UNVIERSITY OF SCIENCE AND TECHNOLOGY

Master Thesis: Diffusion Probabilistic Models For Denoising Micrographs In Cryogenic Electron Microscopy (in collaboration with ETHZ)

Achievements

- Scholarship of the Minister of Science and Higher Education for Significant Achievements for Students
- Member of the genwro.Al research group led by Prof. Maciej Zięba
- Member of the BioMedical.Al scientific circle

SYDDANSK UNIVERSITAT

2022

Grade: A

2023-2024

Final Grade: A

Bachelor's Degree in Applied Computer Science

WROCLAW UNVIERSITY OF SCIENCE AND TECHNOLOGY

Activities

- Member of BioMedical.Al scientific circle
- Member of KN Robocik scientific circle

PUBLICATIONS

Piotr Miłkowski*, **Konrad Karanowski***, Patryk Wielopolski, Jan Kocoń, Przemysław Kazienko, and Maciej Zięba (2023). *Modeling Uncertainty in Personalized Emotion Prediction with Normalizing Flows*. 2023 IEEE International Conference on Data Mining Workshops (ICDMW), 757-766. [* - denotes equal contribution]

Kamil Kanclerz, **Konrad Karanowski**, Julita Bielaniewicz, Marcin Gruza, Piotr Miłkowski, Jan Kocoń and Przemysław Kazienko. *PALS: Personalized Active Learning for Subjective Tasks in NLP* Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (2023).

Marcin Sendera, Marcin Przewięźlikowski, Jan Miksa, Mateusz Rajski, **Konrad Karanowski**, Maciej Zięba, Jacek Tabor and Przemysław Spurek. *The general framework for few-shot learning by kernel HyperNetworks* Machine Vision and Applications 34 (2023): 1-16.

Konrad Karanowski*, Adam R. Chłopowiec*, Tomasz Skrzypczak, Mateusz Grzesiuk, Adrian B. Chłopowiec and Martin Tabakov. *Counteracting Data Bias and Class Imbalance—Towards a Useful and Reliable Retinal Disease Recognition System* Diagnostics 13 (2023): n. pag. [* - denotes equal contribution]

Martin Tabakov, Krzysztof Galus, Artur Zawisza, Adam R. Chłopowiec, Adrian B. Chłopowiec and **Konrad Karanowski**. *Synthetic Data Generation for Morphological Analyses of Histopathology Images with Deep Learning Models* Vietnam. J. Comput. Sci. 10 (2023): 373-389.

Przemysław Kazienko, Julita Bielaniewicz, Marcin Gruza, Kamil Kanclerz, **Konrad Karanowski**, Piotr Miłkowski and Jan Kocoń. *Human-centered neural reasoning for subjective content processing: Hate speech, emotions, and humor.* Inf. Fusion 94 (2023): 43-65.

Maciej Zamorski, Michał Stypułkowski, **Konrad Karanowski**, Tomasz Trzciński and Maciej Zięba (2022). *Continual learning on 3D point clouds with random compressed rehearsal*. Comput. Vis. Image Underst., 228, 103621.

Marcin Sendera, Marcin Przewięźlikowski, **Konrad Karanowski**, Maciej Zięba, Jacek Tabor and Przemysław Spurek. *HyperShot: Few-Shot Learning by Kernel HyperNetworks* 2023 IEEE/CVF Winter Conference on Applications of Computer Vision (WACV) (2022): 2468-2477. DOI: 10.1109/WACV56688.2023.00250

Julita Bielaniewicz, Kamil Kanclerz, Piotr Miłkowski, Marcin Gruza, **Konrad Karanowski**, Przemysław Kazienko and Jan Kocoń. *Deep-SHEEP: Sense of Humor Extraction from Embeddings in the Personalized Context* 2022 IEEE International Conference on Data Mining Workshops (ICDMW) (2022): 967-974.

Martin Tabakov, **Konrad Karanowski**, Adam R. Chłopowiec, Adrian B. Chłopowiec and Mikolaj Kasperek. *Data Augmentation for Morphological Analysis of Histopathological Images Using Deep Learning* International Conference on Computational Collective Intelligence(2022).

Kamil Kanclerz, Marcin Gruza, **Konrad Karanowski**, Julita Bielaniewicz, Piotr Miłkowski, Jan Kocoń and Przemysław Kazienko. *What If Ground Truth Is Subjective? Personalized Deep Neural Hate Speech Detection* NLPERSPECTIVES (2022).

Artur Zawisza, Martin Tabakov, **Konrad Karanowski** and Krzysztof Galus. *Morphological Analysis of Histopathological Images Using Deep Learning* International Conference on Computational Collective Intelligence (2021).

HOBBIES

Composing orchestral music

• Playing the guitar

LANGUAGES

- Polish Native
- English B2/C1